(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
重大告知あり！！
Important announcement!!
Music Garden.
Takane Lui Birthday Live 2025.
はい、尾丸ポルカです。よろしくお願いします。
Hi, I'm Omaru Polka. Nice to meet you.
こんばんは。司会の白上フブキです。よろしくお願いします。
Good evening. I'm your host, Shirakami Fubuki. Nice to meet you.
さて、今夜も始まりました、MUSIC GARDENでございますけれども。
Well, another night of MUSIC GARDEN has begun.
なんか久しぶりだね。
It's been a while, hasn't it?
はい、約2年ぶりに復活...
Yes, back after about two years...
ということでですね...
So then...
復活 おめでたいね
It's great to have the show back.
そうですね
Indeed.
髪切った？
Did you get a haircut?
あ、切ってないんですけども、2年前もそんなこと言ってましたね
Oh, I didn't, but you said the same thing two years ago.
そうだっけ？
Did I?
そうですよ。ポルカさんもお変わりなく
Yes, you did. And you haven't changed either, Polka-san.
ま、はい、元気でやってるわ
Well, yes, I'm doing fine.
それは良かったです。
That's good to hear.
ポルカさんの元気にも負けないくらい、今回元気なゲストさんもいますので
We have some very energetic guests today who can match even your energy, Polka-san.
んー、それは楽しみだね
Hmm, I'm looking forward to that.
はい、では早速紹介していきましょう。本日のゲストのご登場です！
Yes, let's introduce them right away. Here come today's guests!
音乃瀬 奏
Otonose Kanade
猫又 おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
大神 ミオ
Ookami Mio
百鬼 あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
鷹嶺 ルイ
Takane Lui
今夜も豪華ゲストでお送りするMUSIC GARDEN。
Tonight's MUSIC GARDEN features a star-studded lineup.
なんと今夜は、あっ！と驚くような仕掛けいっぱいで お送りするみたいですよ。
And apparently, it's packed with surprising gimmicks.
最後まで見逃せません！
Don't miss out until the very end!
あー、どんな仕掛けなんだろうね？
Ah, I wonder what kind of gimmicks they are.
えー、鷹嶺ルイ君
Um, Takane Lui-kun.
はい
Yes.
MUSIC GARDENといえば、ま、鷹嶺ルイ君だから。今日は誕生日ということで
When it comes to MUSIC GARDEN, well, it's all about Takane Lui-kun. And today is your birthday.
はい、ありがとうございます。そうなんですよ、今日誕生日なんですよ
Yes, thank you. That's right, today is my birthday.
2年ぶりに復活したけど、どう？緊張してる？
It's back after two years, how do you feel? Are you nervous?
はい、緊張してます。
Yes, I am nervous.
でも復活にふさわしい場にできるんじゃないかなと思っているので、楽しみにしていてください
But I believe we can make this a worthy comeback, so please look forward to it.
復活、お花の匂いしますね
The comeback... smells like flowers.
え？ちゃんと風呂入ってきた？
Eh? Did you take a bath properly?
いや、その匂いじゃありませんね、それじゃないですよ
No, it's not that kind of smell. Not that.
あ、そっかそっか
Ah, I see, I see.
今日は一曲目の披露だよね
You're performing the first song today, right?
はい、このあとすぐに披露させていただきます
Yes, I'll be performing it right after this.
はい、一曲目は鷹嶺ルイさんに、アニメの主題歌でも話題でした、
Yes, for the first song, Takane Lui will perform a track that was popular as an anime theme song...
『BOW AND ARROW』を披露していただきます
'BOW AND ARROW'.
ほう、『BOW AND ARROW』。あのフィギュアスケートの...
Oh, 'BOW AND ARROW'. The one with the figure skating...
はい、今回は特別に、フィギュアスケート風のダンスを踊ってくださる
Yes, this time I'll be performing with dancers who will be doing
ダンサーさんと一緒にパフォーマンスをさせていただきます
a figure-skating style dance performance.
おおー、それは楽しみだな
Oh, I'm looking forward to that.
そうですね。それではスタンバイの方、よろしくお願いします
Indeed. Well then, please get ready.
はい、よろしくお願いします
Yes, thank you.
ねえ、あれ。猫又君と音乃瀬君と大神君...あ、初登場だっけ？
Hey, about Nekomata-kun, Otonose-kun, and Ookami-kun... oh, is it their first time here?
そうなんです
That's right.
あ、はい
Ah, okay.
んー、音乃瀬君緊張してるんじゃない？
Hmm, Otonose-kun, aren't you nervous?
もう全然大丈夫ですよ！
I'm totally fine!
行けます！
I can do this!
おお、元気だね
Oh, you're energetic.
元気だねー
So energetic.
そして2回目の登場が、なきり君
And appearing for the second time is Nakiri-kun.
はい、お久しぶりです
Yes, it's been a while.
今日はお昼にシュークリーム食べた？
Did you eat cream puffs for lunch today?
えー、ちょっと今日まだ、今日は食べてない
Eh, well... I haven't eaten any yet today.
あ、そっかそっか。まあ、あとでね、ゆっくりね、食べてね
Ah, I see. Well, eat some later at your leisure.
はい、いっぱい食べます
Yes, I'll eat plenty.
えー、後ほど皆さんともゆっくりお話しさせていただこうと思います。
Well, I'll talk more with everyone later.
さて、スタンバイができたみたいですね。
It looks like the preparations are complete.
アニメをリスペクトしたダンスにもご注目ください。
Please pay attention to the dance that respects the anime.
鷹嶺ルイで、『BOW AND ARROW』
Takane Lui, 'BOW AND ARROW'.
気づけば靴は汚れ 錆びついた諸刃を伝う雨
Before I knew it, my shoes were dirty; rain running down a rusted double-edged blade...
憧れはそのままに 夢から目覚めた先には夢
My yearning remains the same; having awakened from a dream, there is only another dream.
聞こえたその泣き声 消え入る手前の細いソワレ
I heard that crying voice; a faint soirée on the verge of fading away.
憧れのその先へ うずくまる君を見つけるため
To the other side of my yearning, to find you crouched there.
行け 行け 追いつけない速度で 飛べ インパルスに任せて
Go, go, at a speed no one can catch up with; fly, leaving it all to impulse.
...行け　追い抜けない速度で　飛べ　インフレ加速して
...Go, at a speed that can't be overtaken. Fly, accelerating inflation.
行け　きっとこの時を感じる為に生まれてきたんだ
Go, I'm sure I was born to feel this moment.
未来を掴んで　期待値を超えて　額に吹き刺す風
Seize the future, exceed expectations, the wind blowing against my forehead.
今に見なよ　きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
Just watch, surely everyone will notice your brilliance.
相応しい声で　視線追い越して　虚空を超えて行け
With a suitable voice, overtaking gazes, go beyond the void.
見失えていく君の指から今　手を放す
Now, I let go of your hand that's fading from sight.
気づけば謎は解かれ　木目ごと見慣れた板の上
If I notice, the mystery is solved, on the board familiar with the grain.
あの頃憧れたような大人になれたかな
Have I become the adult I admired back then?
そう君の苦悩は君が自分で選んだ痛みだ
Yes, your suffering is the pain you chose yourself.
そして掴んだあの煌めきも全て君のものだ
And that brilliance you grasped is all yours.
僕は弓になって　君のしなだ手の手の平をとって強く引いた
I became a bow, took your withered palm and pulled hard.
今君は決して風に流れない矢になって
Now you've become an arrow that will never be swept away by the wind.
行け　行け　決して振り向かないで　飛べ　もう届かない場所へ
Go, go, never look back. Fly, to a place no longer reachable.
行け　行け　行け　君はいつだって輝いていた
Go, go, go, you were always shining.
未来を掴んで　期待値を超えて　額に吹き刺す風
Seize the future, exceed expectations, the wind blowing against my forehead.
今に見なよ　きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
Just watch, surely everyone will notice your brilliance.
相応しい声で　視線追い越して　虚空を超えて行け
With a suitable voice, overtaking gazes, go beyond the void.
見失えていく君の指から今　手を放す
Now, I let go of your hand that's fading from sight.
はい、続いてはねこたかです。
Yes, next up is Nekotaka.
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you.
二人はどういう関係なの？
What kind of relationship do you two have?
パーティ仲間です。
We're party companions.
パーティ？
Party?
はい。よくルイの家で勝手にパーティ開催してます。
Yes. We often hold parties at Lui's house without permission.
勝手に？！まあ、仲が良くてもですね、人の家で勝手にパーティはしないと思うんですけどもね。
Without permission?! Well, even if you're close, I don't think you should hold parties at someone's house without permission.
いやいや、そうなんですけど。最初私もね、すごい驚いたんですが。
No no, that's true. At first, I was really surprised too.
最近ではね、もう私から「次いつパーティ？」って言うくらいにはね、虜になっちゃってますね。
But lately, I've become so hooked that I'm the one asking, "When's the next party?"
おおー、これは猫又君の策略かな？
Oh, is this Nekomata-kun's strategy?
こうなると思ってました。
I thought it would turn out like this.
ポルさんも今度どうですか、パーティ。
Pol-san, how about you come to a party next time?
パーティっていうのは、私も行っていいのかな？
A party... can I go too?
ぜひぜひ。
By all means.
あ、やっぱり猫又君が許可出すんだね。
Ah, so it's Nekomata-kun who gives the permission.
ねー。楽しそうですね。
Right. Sounds like fun.
フブさんもぜひ。
Fubu-san too, please.
え、あ、じゃあこの後にでも行きましょうかポルさんね。
Eh, oh, then let's go after this, Pol-san.
お、俺、鷹嶺君が苦笑いしてるんですけど。
O-oi, Takane-kun is giving a wry smile though.
なんか勝手にね、出されちゃいましたけども。
They kind of just put me on the spot.
ですけども。まあそんな二人にはですね、かっこよさが詰まったダークチックな曲を披露していただきます。
Well, however. For those two, they will perform a dark-ish song full of coolness.
闇落ちしてるじゃないですか。
Aren't we falling into darkness?
そうなんですよ。でもね、あのねこたかならではの低音を活かした、かっこいいパフォーマンスをしますので楽しみにしてください。
That right. But we'll give a cool performance making use of Nekotaka's signature low tones, so please look forward to it.
はい。ではスタンバイお願いします。
Okay. Then, please stand by.
はい。よろしくお願いします。
Yes. Thank you.
にゃー、仲が良さそうでいいですね。
Nya, it's nice that they're so close.
まあ、ぶっちゃけあれは鷹嶺君もまんざらでもなさそうだよ。
Well, to be honest, it looks like Takane-kun doesn't mind it either.
ねー、そうですね。我々もパーティに混ざっていいみたいですから。
Right, yeah. It seems like we can join the party too.
なんかルイさんの作るポテトサラダが絶品らしいのでね。
I heard the potato salad Lui-san makes is exquisite.
お、なんか詳しいね。
Oh, you're well-informed.
ままままま。ということでスタンバイができたみたいですね。
Ma ma ma ma ma. Anyway, it looks like they're ready.
ん？なんか隠し事か？
Hmm? Some secret?
いえいえいえ。それでは参りましょう。ねこたかで「フィクサー」。
No no no. Let's begin. Nekotaka with "Fixer".
今日までの記憶の全部を消してしまう時まで眠れない
I can't sleep until I erase all my memories up to today.
あしたから生きていく自分の身代わりが欲しくて堪らない
I'm dying for a substitute for myself to live on from tomorrow.
大丈夫と言わせて　後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Let me say I'm okay, and won't you let me blame it on you later?
今更意味ないから後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Since it's too late now, won't you let me blame it on you later?
出来ない約束をとうとうと溢れる一言一言ばかりに脳を奪われるくらい
To the point where my brain is overtaken by every single word that flows from impossible promises
意味を成せない 何も出来ない
I can't make sense of it, I can't do anything
見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい やめたい 逸らせない だから
I can't see, I want to run, I want to fly, I want to stop, I can't look away, so...
沈め沈め 這い上がれないほどまで
Sink, sink, until you can't climb back up
飽きるまで 落とせ落とせ 救い垂らす時まで
Until you get tired, let it fall, let it fall, until the moment salvation is offered
虚飾の粒々を喉から絞め出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
Crushing the grains of vanity along with the screams squeezed out of the throat
笑顔が下手なばっかで 知ったような口振りに沿ってやり過ごす
Just being bad at smiling, I get by following a know-it-all tone
なりたくなかった
I didn't want to be like this
今日役立つ眠たい眠たい理想で救われることを待つ
Waiting to be saved by the sleepy, sleepy ideals that are useful today
一番目はいいの口で言う
Saying the first one with the mouth
力強く固く痛く噛み締めて
Bite down hard, strongly, painfully
死んでしまえ死んでしまえ この先も過去も知らず 嫌いなら
Die, die, knowing neither the future nor the past, if you hate me
壊せ壊せ どうせなら加害者になればいい
Break it, break it, you might as well become the perpetrator
食べきれない苛立ちも何も生まない悲しみも
The frustrations I can't finish eating, the sadness that produces nothing
味気なくて吐き出す前に もうもう次を歌え
Before spitting out the tastelessness, sing, sing the next one
沈め沈め
Sink, sink
落とせ落とせ
Let it fall, let it fall
踊り踊れ 灰色になり切る前に 打ち鳴らせ
Dance, dance, before turning completely grey, strike it out
変われ変われ 眠り落ちる時まで
Change, change, until the moment you fall asleep
どうせなら 奪え奪え 飼い慣らした嘘暴いて
If anything, take it, take it, exposing the tamed lies
煮え滾る頭に過ぎった虚像を見ていた
I was looking at the virtual image that passed through my boiling head
自分を見ていた
I was looking at myself
続いてはルイなでのお二人です。
Next up are the two from Luinade.
ろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！
元気がいいなあ。
They're so energetic.
また言ってる。
She's saying it again.
二人は先輩と後輩なんだよね。
You two are senior and junior, right?
はい。
Yes.
よく話すの？
Do you talk often?
はい、よくご飯に行ったりしてます。
Yes, we often go out for meals.
お、ご飯！いいね。
Oh, meals! That's nice.
何食べんの？
What do you eat?
主にしゃぶしゃぶですかね。
Mostly shabu-shabu, I guess.
しゃぶしゃぶか。
Shabu-shabu, huh?
一緒の鍋をつつく関係、これいいね。
Sharing a hot pot, that's a good relationship.
実はポルさんに相談がありまして。
Actually, I have something to consult Polka-san about.
ポルさんに相談･･･？
Consulting Polka-san...?
ルイ先輩はいつまで経ってもね、奏のお母さんにはなってくれないんですよ。
Lui-senpai won't become Kanade's mom, no matter how much time passes.
お母さん？
Mom?
え、言ってやってくださいよ。
Hey, please tell her.
先輩お母さんにするの？
You want her to be your mom?
もちろんもちろん、奏はいつだって優しいお母さんになってくださる方々を募集してます。よろしくお願いします。
Of course, of course. Kanade is always recruiting people who will be a kind mom to her. Please!
え、じゃあなんでお母さんになってあげないの？逆に。
Well, then why won't you be her mom? On the contrary.
いやなんか、奏は娘って感じがしないというか、娘になったらなんか手がかかりすぎてちょっと責任が持てないなって感じなので、ちょっと親戚ポジションでいいかなって感じですね。
Well, Kanade doesn't really feel like a daughter, if she became my daughter, she'd be too much trouble and I couldn't take responsibility, so I think a relative position is fine.
結構壮大？
Is it quite grand?
壮大かな？
Is it grand?
音乃瀬くんはじゃあ、他にもママがいるの？
Otonose-kun, then, do you have other mamas?
もちろんもちろん！
Of course, of course!
じゃあ要らないでしょ！何で欲しいの？
Then you don't need one! Why do you want more?
それはね、頼れる人は一杯いたほうがいいじゃないですか。
Well, the more people you can rely on, the better, right?
え、じゃあ逆にポルさん奏のお父さんになってくれませんか？
Hey, then on the contrary, Polka-san, won't you be Kanade's dad?
お父さん？
Dad?
どうですか？
How about it?
いや、その意見は倒産ってな！
No, I declare that opinion 'bankrupt'! (Pun on dad)
はい。えーではですね、ルイなでにはこの後「名前のない怪物」を披露していただきます！
Yes. Well then, Luinade will perform 'Namae no Nai Kaibutsu' next!
なんでこの曲選んだの？
Why did you choose this song?
え、もう、すぐ、すぐ行けるんだ、そうやって。
Oh, you're going straight to the point just like that.
私がですね、EGOISTが大好きで、
Well, I really love EGOIST,
その中でもこの曲がすごい大好きなんですけど、
and this song is one of my absolute favorites.
奏の初めての歌ってみたがこの曲で、
This was also Kanade-chan's first cover song,
いつか一緒に歌いたいなと思ってこの曲にしました。
so I chose it because I wanted to sing it with her someday.
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
それではですね、お二人ともスタンバイ、お願いします。
Well then, both of you, please get ready.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, please.
なんかハチャメチャな子だね。
What a crazy kid.
そうですね。
Yes, she is.
なんかよく月曜日に源月を突きつけたりしてるみたいですよ。
It seems she often points a sword at people on Mondays.
あぁ、罪深い。
Oh, how sinful.
クソガキだ。
She's a brat.
クソガキですね、はい。
She is a brat, indeed.
まあしかし歌で見せてくれるので、ギャップ萌えしてる人も多いんじゃないかなと思います。
But she shows her talent through singing,
so many people are charmed by the 'gap'.
鷹嶺君も歌うとかっこいいのに、なんかポンコツだからね。
Takane-kun is cool when singing too,
but she's a bit of a klutz otherwise.
そうですね。
Yes, that's right.
まあギャップがある二人って感じじゃないでしょうかね。
They're a pair with a lot of 'gaps', aren't they?
はい、では参りましょう。
Well then, let's get started.
るいなでで『名前のない怪物』。
Lui-Kana with 'Monster Without a Name'.
名前のない怪物
Monster Without a Name
作詞・作曲：ryo(supercell)
Lyrics/Composition: ryo(supercell)
御伽話は
Fairy tales are...
さっき死んだみたい
...as if they just died.
煉瓦の病棟で
In the brick ward,
うまく歌えなくて
I couldn't sing well.
霧に煙る夜
On a night misty with fog,
浮かべ赤い月
float a red moon.
ほらみて 私を
Look at me,
目を逸らさないで
don't look away.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars,
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born.
悪意の代償を願え
Wish for the price of malice,
望むがままにお前に
to you, as you desire.
さあ 喰らえ正義を
Now, devour justice.
壊して 壊される前に
Break it, before you are broken.
因果の代償を払い
Pay the price of causality,
共にいこう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, monster without a name.
耳鳴りがしてる
My ears are ringing.
鉄条網うるさくて
The barbed wire is so noisy.
思い出せないの
I can't remember...
あの日の旋律
...the melody of that day.
雨はまだやまない
The rain still hasn't stopped.
何にも見えないの
I can't see anything.
ほらみて こんなに
Look, it's become...
大きくなったの
...this big.
黒い雨 降らせこの空
Make black rain fall from this sky.
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis,
愛す同罪の傍観者達に
to the beloved, equally guilty bystanders.
さあ 今 ふるえ正義を
Now, brandish justice.
消せない 傷抱きしめて
Embracing the wounds that won't disappear,
この身体を受け入れ
accepting this body,
共にいこう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, monster without a name.
ああ
Ah...
神が告げる 真世界を
God proclaims the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars...
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born into this world
悪意の代償を願え
Wish for the price of malice
望むがままにお前に
Just as you desired, to you
さあ　震えよう正義を
Now, let's brandish justice
壊して　壊される前に
Destroy it, before being destroyed
因果の代償を払い
Paying the price of karma
報いよ　名もなき怪物
Take your reward, nameless monster
黒い雨　降らせこの空
Black rain, make it fall from this sky
私は望まれないもの
I am something unwanted
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis
愛と憎悪の傍観者たちに
To the bystanders of love and hatred
さあ今　震えよう正義を
Now, let's brandish justice
消さない傷を抱きしめて
Embracing the wounds that won't fade
この身体を受け入れ
Accepting this body
共に行こう　名もなき怪物
Let's go together, nameless monster
さて、ここからは...
Now, from here...
楠木ともりが　鷹嶺ルイ生誕記念グッズ2025をご紹介！
Kusunoki Tomori introduces Takane Lui Birthday Celebration Goods 2025!
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド。
Glittery Acrylic Stand.
キラキラなラメ入りアクリルスタンドが、とってもおしゃれな一品。
The sparkling glittery acrylic stand is a very stylish item.
光を浴びるたびに、きめ細やかなラメがキラキラと輝きを放ちます。
Every time it catches the light, the fine glitter sparkles brilliantly.
光り輝くアクリルスタンドで、あなたの生活もさらに明るくなるでしょう。
This shining acrylic stand will surely make your life even brighter.
ロック風パーカー。
Rock-style Hoodie.
イベントやライブで着るだけでなく、日常にも溶け込むロック風パーカー。
A rock-style hoodie that fits into daily life, not just for events and lives.
前にジップがついているので、部屋着でも普段着でも使いやすい！
With a front zipper, it's easy to use as loungewear or everyday clothes!
ゆるかわバケットハット。
Loose-cute Bucket Hat.
つくねとつみれがワンポイントになっていて、シンプルおしゃかわ。
Featuring Tsukune and Tsumire accents, it's simple and stylishly cute.
普段使いしやすいデザインで、手軽におしゃれ度アップ。
With a design for everyday use, it effortlessly boosts your style.
カジュアル、ストリート、古着MIXなど、幅広いスタイルにマッチ。
It matches a wide range of styles like casual, street, and vintage mixes.
「え？」Tシャツ。
“Eh?” T-shirt.
ルイッシュでおなじみのセリフ「え？」をモチーフにネタTとして堂々発売。
Released as a gag T-shirt featuring her familiar catchphrase “Eh?” from Lui-shu.
どんなコーディネートにも合う白で、夏は単体で、
In white to match any outfit, wear it alone in summer,
冬はパーカーと合わせてインナーとして、一年を通して使えます。
and pair it with a hoodie in winter; it can be used all year round.
全部セットは数量限定もアリ！
Full sets are also available in limited quantities!
鷹嶺ルイ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード特典。
Takane Lui handwritten signature & gold-stamped message postcard bonus.
hololive 公式ECサイトへ急げ！！
Hurry to the hololive official EC site!!
続いてはミオルイです！
Next up is MioLui!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to us!
なかなか... この二人っていうのは珍しいよね？
Quite... This pair is rare, isn't it?
そうですかねー？
Is that so?
結構ね、あの、お話はしたり仲良いんですよ。
We actually, um, talk quite a bit and are close.
うーん、何について話してるの？
Hmm, what do you talk about?
えー、主に、まあ私がそもそもミオしゃの歌が本当に大好きで、
Well, mainly, I really love Mio-sha's singing to begin with,
よく歌のお話をしたりとか、あと個人的に私の悩みを、
so we often talk about songs, and also she listens to my personal worries,
聞いてもらったりとかしてますね。はい。
things like that. Yes.
頼りがいあるからね。
Because she's reliable.
じゃあその何か特別なエピソードとか、あったりする？
Then, do you have any special episodes or something?
特別なエピソードっていうと、私がちょっとしょぼんとした時があったんですけど、
Talking about special episodes, there was a time when I was feeling a bit down,
その時にパーティーを開いてくれまして、
and she held a party for me then.
その時にミオしゃが花束をプレゼントしてくれたんですよ。
At that time, Mio-sha presented me with a bouquet.
覚えてる、覚えてる！
I remember, I remember!
ルイの色のね、花束。
The bouquet in Lui's colors.
そう、ルイカラーのね、あの花束をプレゼントしてくれて、花瓶も持ってたもんね。
Yes, Lui-colored, she gave me that bouquet, and you even brought a vase.
そう、花瓶も！
Right, a vase too!
それがすごい綺麗で、曇ってた心が、一瞬にして晴れましたね。はい。
It was so beautiful, my cloudy heart cleared up in an instant. Yes.
あー、素敵だね。
Oh, that's lovely.
大神さんはよく花とか買うの？
Ookami-san, do you often buy flowers?
あ、はい。お花すごい大好きで、
Ah, yes. I really love flowers,
うちも落ち込んだ時とかに、花を買う時、結構あるんですけど、
I also often buy flowers when I'm feeling down,
猫が食べちゃうんで、まああんまり買えないんですけど。
but my cats eat them, so I can't buy them very often.
さっき聞き逃してたけど、君たちもよくパーティーするんだね。
I missed it earlier, but you guys also do parties often.
そうですね。まあでもおかゆと同じパーティーです。
That's right. Well, but it's the same party as Okayu's.
そうですね、あの、私もよく実は参加させていただいております。
Indeed, um, I actually participate often too.
さっき隠してたのって、白上くんも参加してるってこと？
Were you hiding earlier that Shirakami-kun also participates?
あ、そうですね。ミオさんのオムライスとおかゆさんのポテトサラダは、もう本当にめちゃめちゃ絶品なんです。
Ah, yes. Mio-san's omurice and Okayu-san's potato salad are just truly, incredibly superb.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
いや、ちょっと収拾つかなくなりそうなんで、スタンバイお願いします。
Well, it seems things are getting a bit out of hand, so please stand by.
はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yes, looking forward to it!
またパーティーしようねー！
Let's have a party again!
パーティーパーティー！
Party, party!
あ、なんか作ったりしてるの？パーティーで。
Oh, so do you make anything at parties?
いやぁ、私はあの食べる専門ですね。
No, I'm more of an eating specialist.
食べる専門。
An eating specialist.
はい。
Yes.
甘やかされてるね。
You're being pampered, aren't you?
そうですね。
That's true.
フブさんも一度いかがですか？
How about you too, Fubu-san?
んんっ、んー。
Mm-mm.
ポルさんも甘えていいってこと？
Are you saying I should be pampered too, Pol-san?
それはちょっと。
Well, that's a bit...
え？
Eh?
それでは参りましょう。みよるいで、Beat Eater。
Now then, let's get started. 'Beat Eater' by Miyorui.
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized that right now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
わかってんだ見せられたからって
I know, just because I was shown
拙な罠にはまるつもりなど無い
I have no intention of falling into a clumsy trap
当たり前が止まんない怖いな
The obvious won't stop, it's scary
もどかしさも正しい命題
Frustration is also a correct proposition
ハロー　湧いてくる束の間の自尊心
Hello, a fleeting sense of self-esteem wells up
そこからはどう見えてる？
How does it look from there?
tell me, tell me
どれだけ僕を救ってくれるの
How much will you save me?
反響していく声　加速して
The echoing voice accelerates
始まりは何処から？
Where does it begin?
それも容赦無い力
That too is a merciless power
身体を支配している満ち足りた用意
A full preparation dominating the body
darli'n' darli'n'
タフに踏んでいくスタイル
A style of stepping tough
まにまに幕を上げるのさ
Raising the curtain as it goes
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
No matter what happens, it's not strange
振りを解き答えになって響きだすよ
Untying the pretense, it becomes the answer and starts to ring out
come over
消えていかない感覚
The sensation that won't fade
飽くまで踊っていたいだけ
I just want to dance to the end
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized that right now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばいなんとなくの呪い
Dangerous, some kind of curse
見透かされてんの鬼
Being seen through by a demon
予想よりうねって長い傾向
A tendency longer and more undulating than expected
不確かなものに囲まれてんだね
Surrounded by uncertain things, aren't we?
そこらじゅうに転がってる蛇足
Superfluous things rolling around everywhere
妄想だって思いのほか重要
Even delusions are unexpectedly important
心に逆らう外れた振舞い
An erratic behavior that defies the heart
早まったのさ引くに引けない様相
It's too late, a situation where one can't back down
ほら手に入れた絶景を撃ち込め
Look, blast the superb view you've obtained
姿を映してアブラカタブラ
Reflect the figure, Abracadabra
道は分かれてたんだ
The path was divided
それも遠い過去から
Even that, from a distant past
全て間違いじゃない悲しみ方
A way of grieving that isn't all wrong
darli'n' darli'n' 満更でもない
darli'n' darli'n' it's not that bad
まにまに塗り直すのさ
Repainting as it goes
今になればいつだって構わない
Now it doesn't matter whenever
色を替え答えになって溢れ出すよ
Changing colors, it becomes the answer and overflows
come over
消えていかない感覚
The sensation that won't fade
まだまだ足りていないみたい
Still doesn't seem to be enough
重なり合う光　痛みに寄り添う
Overlapping lights, snuggling up to pain
何処にも消えないで欲しい
I want it to never disappear
留まる深い重い深淵頼り
Relying on a staying, deep, heavy abyss
傷付くこともある
Sometimes getting hurt
darli'n' darli'n' タフに踏んでいくスタイル
darli'n' darli'n' A style of stepping tough
まにまに対峙するのさ
Confronting as it goes
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
No matter what happens, it's not strange
振りを解き答えになって響きだすよ
Untying the pretense, it becomes the answer and starts to ring out
come over
消えていかない感覚
The sensation that won't fade
飽くまで踊っていたいだけ
I just want to dance to the end
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized that right now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばいなんとなくの呪い
Dangerous, some kind of curse
見透かされてんの鬼
Being seen through by a demon
続いては鷹嶺ルイで。
Next up is Takane Lui.
はい、よろしくお願いします。よろしくお願いします。
Yes, nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
鷹嶺君は何か、最近ハマってるゲームとかあるの？
Takane-kun, is there any game you're into lately?
最近ハマっているゲーム
Games I'm into lately
ハマってるゲームあります。あの最近ってわけでもないんですけど、事務所に入ってから、ドラゴンクエストというゲームに出会いまして。
There is a game I'm into. It's not necessarily 'lately', but ever since I joined the agency, I encountered a game called Dragon Quest.
あー、ドラゴンクエスト。おおー。
Oh, Dragon Quest. Whoa.
ナンバリング1から11までやっていて、派生とかもあるので、本当に面白くてですね、大好きです。
I've played through the main series from 1 to 11, and there are spin-offs too, so it's really interesting and I love it.
あー、ドラクエの、どんなところが魅力？
What's the charm of Dragon Quest?
魅力たくさんあるんですけど、本当に人生の教科書だなって思うことが結構多くてですね。
There are many charms, but I often think it's really like a textbook of life.
ドラゴンクエストは人生の教科書
Dragon Quest is a textbook of life
もちろん悲しいこともあるんですけど、それを仲間たちと支え合って前に進んでいくパワーと...
Of course there are sad things, but there's the power of supporting each other with friends and moving forward...
...ナンバリングが進んでいくにつれてわかる真実とかがあったりとか、長年愛されてる理由が詰まってるなって感じますね。
...and there are truths you discover as you progress through the series. I feel like it's packed with reasons why it's been loved for many years.
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ、ゲーム以外も...
So, besides games...
も、なんかドラクエのそういうイベントとか行ったりしてるの？
So, have you been going to Dragon Quest events and stuff like that?
はい、行ってますね。ドラクエのテーマパークだったりとか、
Yes, I have. Like the Dragon Quest theme park,
あとは限定ショップに行ったりとか。
and going to the limited-time shops.
あとはアニメもあるので、あのファンの人と同時視聴とかしたりしてましたね。はい。
There's also the anime, so I've done watch-alongs with my fans for that. Yes.
充実してんなあ！
You're really living it up!
はい、充実してます。
Yes, it's very fulfilling.
そんなドラクエ大好き鷹嶺ルイさんには、
For Takane Lui-san, who loves Dragon Quest so much,
これからアニメ『ドラゴンクエスト ダイの大冒険』の
she will now perform the first opening song of the anime
初代オープニング「生きるをする」を披露していただきます！
'Dragon Quest: The Adventure of Dai' titled 'Ikiru o Suru'!
はーい！それは楽しみ！
Yay! I'm looking forward to it!
楽しみですね！
We're looking forward to it!
特別な演出にも注目してくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you also pay attention to the special production!
はい！それではスタンバイ、お願いします！
Alright! Then please get ready!
はい！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Thank you!
やー、はまれるものがあるっていうのはいいよね。
Man, it's great to have something you're really into.
いいですよね！
It really is!
何やらこの曲を歌ってほしいというリクエストもかなり多かったみたいですよ。
It seems there were quite a lot of requests for her to sing this song, too.
ほー、ってことはみんな待望ってわけだね。
Oh, so that means everyone's been waiting for this.
ですねー！
Indeed!
あ、それではスタンバイができたみたいなのでいきましょう。
Oh, it looks like she's ready, so let's go.
鷹嶺ルイさんで「生きるをする」です。どうぞ！
Takane Lui with 'Ikiru o Suru'. Please enjoy!
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
That I continue to love myself
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, can I still believe?
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where the journey leads
生きるをする / 作詞・作曲：はっとり
Ikiru o Suru / Lyrics & Composition: Hattori
あれ、いつからだ？本音が弱音になったな
Oh, since when did my true feelings become complaints?
逃げないことが強さになったな
Not running away became a form of strength
なあ、見つからない？
Hey, can't you find it?
自信じゃなく自分自身
Not self-confidence, but my very self
きっとまだ探せてない忘れものがあるはず
There must be something forgotten I haven't found yet
ずっとまだ伝えてない伝えたい言葉
Words I want to convey that I haven't yet
見ててくれるなら魅せてみせるのに
If you're watching, I'd show you something enchanting
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
That I continue to love myself
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, can I still believe?
くすぶるのは、ちゃんと燃えたからだ
Smoldering is because I burned properly
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where the journey leads
ただ、目を見開いて夢を見る
Just, keeping my eyes wide open, I dream
夢を見る
I dream
よう、生きてるかい？
Yo, are you living?
本当の強さ 君だけが分かっていればいいのさ
True strength, it's fine if only you know it
逃げたり 傷ついた数だけ居場所は増えたりする
By running away or getting hurt, your place to belong might increase
見ててくれ 姿じゃなく生き方を
Watch me, not my appearance, but my way of life
僕が僕を愛し抜かなきゃ
I have to continue to love myself
終わらない 迷子の交差点 思い出しの
It won't end, the intersection of being lost, remembering...
悲しみの縫い目に投げキッス
A blown kiss to the seams of sadness
どこへ向かう旅だとしてもさあ
No matter where the journey leads, come on
まだ手を取り合って
Still holding hands
脳、映像、スカイはグレー、夜を駆ける
Brain, images, the sky is gray, racing through the night
束の間、終幕、裏切りは愛のおまけ
A brief moment, the final curtain, betrayal is a bonus of love
かさぶたになる日々 美しくはないのさ
Days that become scabs aren't beautiful
腰に巻いた正義の切れ味はどうだんだ
How's the sharpness of the justice buckled at your waist?
僕らは違う痛みを生きる
We live through different pains
勇敢でいたい 立ち向かいたい
I want to be brave, I want to stand up
眠っていたストーリーをすごいスピードで醒ましたい
I want to wake up the sleeping story at a great speed
僕が僕を愛せる強さを
The strength to be able to love myself
かなり愛してもいいかい？
Is it okay to love quite a lot?
くすぶるのも 燃えカスになるまで
Smoldering until it becomes cinders
どこへ向かう旅だっていいさ いいのさ
Any journey is fine, it's fine
ただ 目を見開いて夢を見る 息をする
Just keeping my eyes wide open, I dream, I breathe
生きるをする
I live
これでも...
Take...
...くらえ！
...THIS!
続いてはおにかんです。
Next up is Onikan.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you for having us.
前回に引き続き、もうお二人は仲が良いね。
As always, the two of you are very close.
はい。
Yes.
仲良いですよ。
We're close.
仲良しです。
We're good friends.
息もぴったりだ。
You're in perfect sync.
なきりさんは今日シュークリーム食べた？
Ayame-san, did you eat cream puffs today?
今日はね、まだ食べてないんですよ。
I haven't eaten any today yet.
でもお弁当食べました。
But I did eat a bento.
お弁当ね、美味しいのあったからね。
The bento was delicious, wasn't it?
美味しかったです。
It was delicious.
はい、私達も後で食べましょうね、ポルさん。
Yes, let's eat some later too, Pol-san.
そうだね、お腹ぺこぺこだからね。
Right. Because I'm starving.
ね。そして何やらお二人、私達MCに聞きたいことがあるらしいですよ。
Right. And it seems you two have something you want to ask us MCs.
はい。
Yes.
何なに？
What is it?
いや、こうやってMUSIC GARDENやってますけど、
Well, we're doing MUSIC GARDEN like this,
お二人は何か歌いたいってなってないですか？
but don't you two ever feel like you want to sing?
歌いてーみたいな。
Like, "I want to sing!"
歌いてーって。
Wanting to sing...
まあ、多少ね。
Well, a little bit.
ふむふむ。口ずさんだり体を動かしたりするけどね。MCだから。
Hmm hmm. I hum and move my body, but I'm the MC.
ね、はい。MCなので。
Right, yes. Since we're the MCs.
じゃあ、本当は歌って踊りたいってことでいいですか？
Then, is it safe to say you actually want to sing and dance?
いや、皆さんのいいパフォーマンス見てたらね。
Well, seeing everyone's great performances...
じゃあ！
Then!
じゃあね！
踊って歌いましょうか！
Shall we dance and sing?
はい、じゃあ立っていただいて。
Yes, so please stand up.
いや、私は...え、いいんですか？え、立っていいんですか？
Eh, ah, I... wait, is it okay? Can we stand up?
あっち側で衣装着替えていただいていいですか？
Could you please go over there and change into your costumes?
衣装？
Costumes?
はい。すぐ行くすぐ行く。すぐ行って。
Yes. Go now, go now. Go right away.
行ってきまーす！
We're going!
じゃあスタンバイしに行ってください。
Then please go get on standby.
はい、じゃあね。こちらで一旦CMです。
Yes, okay. We'll have a commercial break here.
あ、それ私のセリフ！
Ah, that's my line!
お、準備できたかな？大丈夫かな？
Oh, are you ready? Is everything okay?
あ、なんかあったんで着替えましたけども。
Ah, there was something there so we changed.
あ、できました？じゃあ、私たちも行きましょうか。
Oh, you're done? Then, shall we go too?
行きましょう行きましょう。
Let's go, let's go.
じゃあ、ポルさんカンペ読んでください。
Then, Pol-san, please read the cue card.
え、え、
Eh? Eh?
それでは聞いてください。おにかんプラスふぶぽるで、チャンカパーナ。
Then, please listen. Onikan plus FubuPolka, "Chankapana".
深夜バスで君を見た
I saw you on the night bus
息を呑むような黒髪
Black hair that takes my breath away
行き先は違うけれど
Though our destinations were different
オレは迷わず飛び乗る
I jumped on without hesitation
一人じゃ悲しすぎる夜さ
A night that's too sad alone
誰かと話したかった
I wanted to talk to someone
君もうれしそうで
You looked happy too
どちらからともなく 手を握る
And without a word, we held hands
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so much it hurts
もう ジン ジン 燃えている
Already, zing zing, I'm burning up
身体は止まらない
My body won't stop
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
頷いた君 抱きしめた
You nodded and I held you tight
恥じらうその瞳 狂ってしまいそう
Those shy eyes, I'm about to go crazy
夜の吐息のなか チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
In the breath of the night, Chankapana, Chankapana
バスを捨てて二人は
Leaving the bus behind, the two of us
眠れる場所を探した
Looked for a place to sleep
うやうやしく服を脱ぎ
Respectfully taking off our clothes
ベッドに滑り込む花
A flower sliding into bed
この世にも天使がいたのさ
There was an angel in this world too
その肌に触れたんだ
I touched that skin
恋って好きなんて 悪戯に言うから 舞い上がる
When you say "love" or "like" teasingly, I soar
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
人生で一番美味しいもの
The most delicious thing in my life
そう ナン ナン 何度だって 君を抱いていたい
Yes, nan nan, no matter how many times, I want to keep holding you
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
まだまだ君が足りないよ
I still can't get enough of you
露なその果実 狂ってしまいそう
That exposed fruit, I'm about to go crazy
夜よ覚めないでくれ チャンカパーナ
Oh night, please don't end, Chankapana
美しい恋にする
I'll make it a beautiful love
美しい恋にするよ
美しい恋にするから
I'll make it a beautiful love
約束する、チャンカパーナ
I promise, Chankapana
美しすぎて震える... チャンカパーナ
So beautiful I tremble... Chan Kapana
月がふたりを捜すから
Because the moon is searching for us
今夜　世界から身を隠そう
Tonight, let's hide ourselves from the world
覗いたその肌は　褐色のマシュマロだね
That peeking skin is like a brown marshmallow
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ　チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chan Kapana, Chan Kapana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so much it hurts
もう　ジンジン燃えている　身体は止まらない
My body's already burning, and I can't stop
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ　チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chan Kapana, Chan Kapana
オレの腕にしがみついた
Clinging to my arm
華奢なその肩に　狂ってしまいそう
Those delicate shoulders make me feel like I'm going crazy
夜の吐息のなか　チャンカパーナ
In the sighs of the night, Chan Kapana
チャンカパーナ
Chan Kapana
Project "L"
鷹嶺ルイ 1st Album
Takane Lui 1st Album
Liberty 各サイトで好評配信中
Liberty now streaming on various platforms
（笑い声）
(Laughing)
鷹嶺ルイ生誕3Dライブを見ている諸君、お初にお目にかかる。
To all those watching Takane Lui's birthday 3D live, pleased to meet you.
私はゼロ。黒の騎士団の総帥にして世界への反逆者。
I am Zero. Leader of the Black Knights and rebel against the world.
ここまでのエムガはどうだったかな？
How has MUSIC GARDEN been so far?
大いに盛り上がったことだろう。
I'm sure it's been a lot of fun.
ほう。だが、まだ足りないな。
Hmph. But it's not enough yet.
諸君らなら、まだまだ盛り上がれるはずだ。
If it's you lot, I'm sure you can get even more excited.
鷹嶺ルイの歌によってな！
Through Takane Lui's singing!
ルルーシュ・ヴィ・ブリタニアが命じる。
Lelouch vi Britannia commands you.
鷹嶺ルイよ、コードギアスの主題歌メドレーで、さらに盛り上げるのだ！
Takane Lui, liven things up even more with a Code Geass theme song medley!
Yes, Your Highness.
自分を　世界さえも　変えてしまえそうな
Like I could change myself, and even the world
瞬間は　いつもすぐそばに...
That moment is always right by my side...
隠せぬ苛立ちと　立ち尽くす自分を見つめ
Staring at my irritation I can't hide and my standing self
迷いながら　悩みながら　悔やみながら　決めればいいさ
While hesitating, while worrying, while regretting, you can just decide
君がくれた　言葉ひとつ　戸惑いは消え去り
The single word you gave me, and the confusion disappears
空っぽだった　僕の部屋に　光が射した
Light shone into my empty room
見上げた大空が　青く澄み切って行く
The sky I looked up at is becoming clear and blue
閉ざした窓を　開く事を決めた
I decided to open the window I'd closed
自分を　世界さえも　変えてしまえそうな
Like I could change myself, and even the world
瞬間は　いつもすぐそばに...
That moment is always right by my side...
夢見てた夢
The dream I dreamed of
果て無き遠く
Endlessly far away
乾いた日々の　空色　手の中
The sky color of dry days, in my hands
乾いた日々の 空色 手の中
Dry days, the sky's color, in my hands
等間隔 音の中で 試行錯誤
Equidistant, trial and error within the sound
時間・間隔の無い空間 an
A space without time or interval...
等身大 音をたてて
Life-size, making a sound
僕の顔 造って行く
Making my face
キレイに 片方だけ
Beautifully, only one side
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Though I tread the path of beasts, roaring like lions and tigers
茜さす空の 彼方にまほろば
Beyond the madder-red sky lies a fair land
幽囚の孤独に 彷徨う青春は
The youth wandering in the solitude of imprisonment
弱さと怒りが 姿無き敵ですか
Are weakness and anger formless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は 己を知りがたし
Father, I still find it hard to know myself
先立つ兄らの 見えない背中を追えば
If I follow the invisible backs of my preceding brothers
迷いの一夜に 明星は誘う
The morning star beckons in the night of hesitation
死して終わらぬ 夢を焦がれども
Though I yearn for a dream that does not end in death
確かな君こそ 我が命
You, who are certain, are my life
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Living as butterflies and flowers in the gale-swept wilderness
常しえの春に 咲き添う幻
A phantom blooming alongside an eternal spring
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Purity amidst chaos, even if this body is defiled
心の錦を 信じていてください
Please believe in the inner splendor
母よ けして我は 涙を見せねども
Mother, even if I never show you my tears
足下の草に 露は消えもせず
The dew on the grass beneath my feet does not vanish
朝も夜も 恋い焦がれて
Morning and night, I yearn for you
星になるよ 君守る
I'll become a star to protect you
戦いは 行く末知らず
The battle's end is unknown
明日・時・運命をさぜんで
Gathering tomorrow, time, and fate
交わらない 君と僕
You and I, our paths do not cross
今行くよ 僕は流れ星
I'm going now, I'm a shooting star
世界が朽ち果てても 変わることのないものがある
Even if the world decays, there are things that never change
涙をこらえてでも 守るべきものが僕らにはある
Even while holding back tears, we have things worth protecting
何万年何億年前からのメッセージが体内(うち)でうずきだす 鳴り響く
Messages from ages ago start throbbing within me, echoing
しゃがれた声で 明日を呼ぶ 傷だらけの手で 君守る
Calling for tomorrow with a raspy voice, protecting you with scarred hands
I continue to fight I continue to fight
見つめ合い 手と手を重ねて
Gazing at each other, hands overlapping
ガラス越しの 君と僕
You and I, through the glass
こんなにも そばにいるのに
Even though you are so close
暗い闇を 真っ白に染めるよ
I'll dye the dark shadows pure white
出口のない 君の元へ
To your side, where there's no exit
運命を切り裂く 流れ星
A shooting star that tears through fate
あふれる君の涙 僕がいま奪い去る
Your overflowing tears, I will take them away now
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Mosaic pieces, connecting them one by one to paint a picture
あなたがくれた 出会いと別れも
The meetings and partings you gave me too
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
It wasn't supposed to be like this, thinking that as I sleep
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
And when I wake up, it's the same old spinning in circles
意味も無く繰り返し
Repeating without meaning
モザイクカケラ 拾い集めてた「上手く生きる為の術」
Mosaic pieces, I was picking up 'the technique for living well'
歪なそれが 美しく見えたんだ
That distorted thing looked beautiful to me
強がりながら つまずきながら 選び抜いた道の上で
While acting tough, while stumbling, on the path I chose
剥がれ落ちては 埋まらないカケラ
Pieces that flake off and don't fill the gaps
形に落ちては 埋まらないこのカラー
The colors that don't fill the mold
幹部 初配信
Executive First Stream
鷹嶺ルイ コードギアスシリーズ宣伝アンバサダー就任決定
Takane Lui: Appointed as Code Geass Series PR Ambassador
詳細は公式X またはYouTubeチャンネルで
Details on official X or YouTube channel
はい、ということで、特報VTR見ていただきましたけれども。
Alright, so you've just seen the breaking news VTR.
なんと、この鷹嶺ルイ、なんと、なんと！
Believe it or not, I, Takane Lui, believe it or not!
コードギアス、アンバサダーに決定しました！
Have been appointed as the Code Geass Ambassador!
イェーイ！嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
もめちゃくちゃね、コードギアスシリーズ、大、大、大好きなので、
I absolutely, absolutely love the Code Geass series, so
こんな素晴らしい機会をいただけるの、本当に嬉しいでございます。皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
I'm truly happy to have such a wonderful opportunity. It's all thanks to you guys. Thank you so much.
そしてですね、皆さんお気づき...もう気づいてますよね？
And also, as you might have noticed... you already did, didn't you?
もうなんと、ルルーシュ役の福山さんが、鷹嶺ルイと呼んでいただき、演じていただきました。
Mr. Fukuyama, the voice of Lelouch, actually called my name and performed as him!
本当にすごい！こんな豪華なことってあるんですか？いや、本当にありがとうございます。
It's incredible! Can something this luxurious even happen? I'm so grateful.
もうコードギアス・メドレーでもね、あのバックに、はい、あのコードギアスの、アニメーションも、エンディングと、歴代のエンディングとオープニングも流れたということで、
In the Code Geass Medley as well, in the background, animations from the series, including past openings and endings, were shown.
本当に豪華な仕上がりになっていたんですけれども、いかがでしたか皆さん？ね。
It turned out to be a really lavish production. What did you think, everyone?
はい。私もめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです。本当にありがとうございます。
Yeah. I'm so happy. Thank you very much.
アンバサダーとしてのですね、お仕事はですね、歌ってみたを上げたりとか、あとは同時視聴をしたりとか、あとはそのほか、もろもろ、あの、いろいろ盛りだくさんで用意しておりますので、
As for my work as an ambassador, I'll be releasing cover songs, doing watch-alongs, and many other things. We have a lot in store!
詳細はですね、このあと、コードギアスシリーズの公式YouTubeチャンネルにも投稿されますので、ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。
Details will be posted on the official Code Geass YouTube channel later, so please check it out.
もちろん私のXでも、XやYouTubeチャンネルでも、詳細をその都度、あの、伝えていきますので、チャンネル登録、そしてXのフォローもよろしくお願いします。
Of course, I'll also be sharing details on my X account and YouTube channel as they come, so please subscribe and follow me on X.
さて、このあとはですね、新曲を披露させていただきます。
Now then, I'm going to perform my new song.
よっ！来ましたよ、私の新曲が。
Alright! Here it comes, my new song.
ということで、新曲のタイトルはですね、『ZIG-ZAG』という曲になっております。『ZIG-ZAG』というのはですね、トラウマの別称になっているんですけれども、
The title of the new song is "ZIG-ZAG". "Zig-zag" is another name for trauma.
その『ZIG-ZAG』、自分の中にあるトラウマと戦って、前を向いていこうという、かっこいい、かっこよく前を向いていくという、曲になっておりますので、
This song, "ZIG-ZAG," is about fighting the traumas within yourself and moving forward. It's a cool song about facing forward, so
ぜひぜひ、みんなにもちょっと聞いていただいて、「あ、こんなことあるな私」「私もこんなことあるな」と共感していただけたら嬉しいなと思います。
I hope everyone listens to it and can relate, thinking, "Oh, I've felt this way too."
それではじゃあ、曲振りは、コードギアスのアンバサダーにもなったということで、久々にルイシュで行きたいと思います。
Now, since I've become a Code Geass ambassador, I'll do the song intro as "Luish" after a while.
みんな準備はいいか？あ、私の準備もいいか、大丈夫か？ということで、行きますよ。
Is everyone ready? Oh, am I ready? Alright. Here we go.
ルイシュ・ビ・タカネリ・ガ・メイズル。
Luish vi Takaneli commands you.
お前たち、新曲を聴け！
You all, listen to the new song!
One, two, three, four!
「幸せ」って囁いた 問いが ラッタッタラッタ
"Happiness," whispered the question, rat-ta-ta-rat-ta
こびり付いて離れぬわ 駄目だ ラッタッタラッタ
It sticks and won't let go, it's no good, rat-ta-ta-rat-ta
無味無臭の生活が 思い出せないや
I can't remember my tasteless, odorless life anymore
忘れたいから歌った 虚勢だ ラッタッタラッタ
I sang because I wanted to forget, it's a bluff, rat-ta-ta-rat-ta
恨む事も 憎む事も 賢くない故 出来なかった
I couldn't resent or hate, because I wasn't clever enough
これが君の 結末ならば 笑ってしまいたいほど 嗚呼、嗚呼
If this is your end, I want to laugh so hard, ah, ah...
嘘つき
Liar
やだ 痛い痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, wishing for a miracle just a bit
もう 嫌嫌嫌嫌！ タチが悪いわ
Enough, no, no, no, no! It's in bad taste
ねえ 辛い Lie Lie Lie 苦？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, it's painful, lie, lie, lie, suffering? Gouge out everything that's wrong
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
I don't care if I'm heartless, call me whatever you want
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です です です
I want to say bye-bye to trauma, I really do
私、甘え上手になれなかった 可愛げとかが足りなかった
I couldn't be good at being pampered, I lacked cuteness
後悔が喧しい夜だ
It's a night filled with loud regrets
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば きっといいことあるさとか
If I just accept that the past is the past, surely something good will happen...
それくらい百も承知だ ラッタッタ
I know that full well, rat-tat-tat
願う事も祈る事も 許されないから黒く染めた
Since I'm not allowed to wish or pray, I dyed it black
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color
絡んだ運命の糸 糸 糸 糸
The tangled threads of fate, threads, threads, threads...
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, pretending to be a tragic heroine
もう嫌嫌嫌！諦めちゃえば？
Enough, I hate it, hate it, hate it! Why not just give up?
でも会いたい会いたい会いたいな 思考回路がこんがらがっちゃって
But I want to see you, see you, see you, my thought circuits are getting all tangled
明日またきっと壊すけどいいの
I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but that's okay
トラウマさえ愛おしいのです です です ですです
Even trauma is precious to me, it is, it is, it is...
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I'm holding hands with you
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
Just like the two of us back then, when we knew nothing
でもわかっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know, I'll wake up soon
それならばいっそ君の手でそっと トドメ刺して ほら 今今今！
If so, just let your hand gently deliver the final blow, look, now, now, now!
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, wishing for a bit of a miracle
もう嫌嫌嫌！タチが悪いわ
Enough, I hate it, hate it, hate it! It's in bad taste
ねえ辛い Lie Lie Lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, it's painful, Lie Lie Lie, no? Scoop out everything that's wrong
薄情で結構好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless if you like, I don't care
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です です ですです
I want to say bye-bye to trauma, I do, I do, I do...
楽しくお届けしてきましたMUSIC GARDEN、
We've been bringing you MUSIC GARDEN,
あっという間にエンディングの時間となりました。
and in the blink of an eye, it's time for the ending.
ポルカさん今日はいかがでしたか？
Polka-san, how was it today?
いやー、なんか今日は私も一緒に歌って踊っちゃったからね。
Wow, since I sang and danced along today,
いつも以上にボルテージが上がっちゃったね。
the excitement was higher than usual.
あー、あと一時間やりたい！
Ah, I want to do one more hour!
いやいややらないですけども、本当に、もっとやりたいんですけどね。
No, no, we're not doing that, but really, I want to do more too.
グッズ販売とプレミア公開も迫っていますので。
The merch sales and premiere are also coming up.
あーそっかそっか。
Ah, I see, I see.
鷹嶺君、今日はてんこ盛りだったね！
Takane-kun, today was packed!
まさかコードギアス...
I can't believe Code Geass...
貯めてる貯めてる。
Saving it up, saving it up.
私もね、早く言いたくて言いたくてたまらなかったです。
I also really, really wanted to say it sooner.
この後グッズ販売と新曲プレミア公開、
After this, there's merch sales and the new song premiere,
そしてメンバーシップ限定配信もありますので、楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです！
and a membership-only stream, so I hope you enjoy them!
本当にこの後も盛りだくさんだ。
There's really so much more after this.
改めてお誕生日おめでとうね！
Happy birthday again!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
MUSIC GARDEN 2できて本当に嬉しいです。
I'm so happy we could do MUSIC GARDEN 2.
ポルさん、フブさんも、本当にありがとうございました！
Pol-san, Fubu-san, thank you so much too!
いえいえ、ありがとうございます。
No, no, thank you.
さあ、是非ね、また、またやりたいね！
Now, let's definitely do it again!
あー是非またやりたいですね。
Ah, I'd definitely love to do it again.
是非よろしくお願いします。
Yes, please.
せっかくですので、ゲストの皆さんにも感想いただきましょう。
Since they're here, let's get some comments from the guests as well.
皆さんから何か言いたいことがあるみたいですよ。
It seems like everyone has something to say.
おっ！
Oh!
ルイ！
Lui!
お誕生日！
Happy birthday!
おめでとー！！
Congratulations!!
ありがとうございます！みんなと歌えて幸せでした！
Thank you! I was so happy to sing with everyone!
またコラボしよー！
Let's collab again!
是非しよー！やったー！
Let's do it! Yay!
はい、では本当にあっという間ですが、
Alright, it's been a whirlwind,
今夜のMUSIC GARDENはここまでとなります。ありがとうございました！
but tonight's MUSIC GARDEN ends here. Thank you very much!
それではまた、MUSIC GARDEN 3が叶う日まで。
Until the day when MUSIC GARDEN 3 happens.
さようならー！
Goodbye!
ラプやべーぞ！
Lap-chan, this is crazy!
どうしたんや。
What's wrong?
とんでもねーグッズ出るぞ！
Some crazy merch is coming out!
はい？
Huh?
バカすげーグッズが一気に来るぞ！
A ton of super awesome merch is coming out at once!
Tシャツ！
T-shirt!
おお。
Oh.
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド！
Glitter acrylic stand!
おっつー。
Nice.
ゆるカバケットハット！
Yuru-ka bucket hat!
ほしい！
I want it!
ロック風パーカー！
Rock-style hoodie!
着たい！
I want to wear it!
そしてフルセットには直筆...
And the full set includes a hand-written...
直筆サイン入りポストカードがつくぞ！
A hand-signed postcard is included!
なんだってー！
No way!
さらにホロコマもついてくるぞ！
Plus, it comes with a Holokoma too!
うわぁぁー！
Waaaa!
これは買いでしょう！
This is a must-buy, right?
MUSIC GARDEN
TAKANE LUI Birthday 2025
2025.6.11.WED 20:00 Lui Ch.
重大告知あり！！
Major announcement!!